A Guide to the Thomas H. Hunter Collection 1934-1995
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
The Thomas H. Hunter Collection 1934-1995
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-4
Hunter main collection of career papers and assorted objects 118 boxes 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 Hunter addition of mainly family correspondence and memorabilia and interviews with Hunter from 1993 to 1997; 15 boxes, 14 boxes are 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm, 1 box is 27 cm x 33 cm x 41 cm
Collected by Thomas H. Hunter, Anne Hunter, and John Owen.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Harrison Hunter was born in Chicago on October 12, 1913. Despite a childhood bout with polio that left him on crutches from the age of seven, Hunter was a coxswain on the crew teams at both Harvard and Cambridge, where he was a Henry Fellow at Trinity Hall. He completed his medical education at Harvard Medical School.
During his internship and residency training at Columbia University Presbyterian Hospital in New York, Hunter began the clinical research that would lead to a dual antibiotic treatment for bacterial endocarditis, an infection of the heart's lining and valves that had previously been uniformly fatal.
Hunter was Dean of the University of Virginia School of Medicine from 1953 to 1965, Chancellor for Medical Affairs from 1965 to 1970, and Vice President for Medical Affairs from 1970 to 1971. In 1970 he received the Thomas Jefferson Award, the highest honor bestowed by the University of Virginia. In 1973 he received the Raven Award for excellence in service and contribution to the University. In 1971 Hunter was named Owen R. Cheatham Professor of Science, co-founding the model Program in Human Biology and Society with Joseph Fletcher. In addition he served as President of the American Association of Medical Colleges (AAMC) and Treasurer of the Pan American Federation of Associations of Medical Schools (PAFAMS), of which he was a founder.
Thomas H. Hunter was deeply interested in international medicine, arguing that health and medicine provide a uniquely powerful bridge to international understanding. In his presidential address to the AAMC in 1960, Hunter called the attention of the United States medical community to its opportunities and responsibilities in other countries. Accompanied by his wife, Anne Fulcher Hunter and their five children, Hunter spent a year teaching in Cali, Colombia as a representative of the Rockefeller Foundation. He also worked and taught in Egypt, Venezuela, Tunisia, Kenya, Cameroon, Chile, and Brazil. The Thomas H. Hunter Professorship of International Medicine was established in 1989 by the University of Virginia Medical School.
Throughout his career, Thomas H. Hunter served in an advisory capacity to numerous medical schools in the United States and was a pioneer in the field of bioethics. His life was characterized by the promulgation of scientific excellence combined with human compassion. Thomas H. Hunter died on October 23, 1997 at his home in Cismont, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
The Thomas H. Hunter Collection comprises 118 boxes of official correspondence, statistical reports, ledgers and appointment books, photographs, medals and certificates, student notebooks, conference booklets, reprints of scientific and administrative articles, microscope slides, cassettes, and videotapes.
The Hunter Addition to the Thomas H. Hunter Collection consists of fourteen boxes of personal papers which complement the original collection.
Contents List
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1968-1981, 23 TL (CC) (Box-folder 1-1)
  A File
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1972, 5 ALS, ANS (Box-folder 1-2)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1955-1981, 27 TLS (Box-folder 1-3)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1968-1979, 15 TLS/TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 1-4)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS 1977/ca, 3 Pamphlets (Box-folder 1-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS ANNOUNCEMENT AND QUESTIONNAIRE 1968, 2 Printed Forms (Box-folder 1-6)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1965-1977, 16 TMs (P), AMs (Box-folder 1-7)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER'S CURRICULUM VITAE 1990, 6 pp. c.v. (Box-folder 1-8)
  Acquired 11-13-97 From Department of Internal Medicine (JMT)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1977, 15 TLS (Box-folder 2-1)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1968-1977, 18 TL (CC) (Box-folder 2-2)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1976, 8 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 2-3)
- RAYMOND BERNARD ALLEN TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1968-1970, 3 ALS (Box-folder 2-4)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPY SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER N.D., ALS (P) (Box-folder 2-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1968-1970, 6 TMs (P) (Box-folder 2-6)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINT, NEWSCLIPPING, MEMBERSHIP CARD 1964-1973, 2 Reprints/Newsclippings, Printed Card (Box-folder 2-7)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1968-1971, 10 TMs (P) (Box-folder 2-8)
  AID 1
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1980-1981, 3 TLS (Box-folder 2-9)
  AIS (Academy of Independent Scholars)
- ACADEMY OF INDEPENDENT SCHOLARS NOMINATIONS, MEMBERSHIP CARD 1981/ca, 2 Printed Forms, Printed Card (Box-folder 2-10)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1979-1980, 3 TMs/TMs (P) (Box-folder 2-11)
- ACADEMY OF INDEPENDENT SCHOLARS PROSPECTUS N.D., Pamphlet (Box-folder 2-12)
- MEMOS SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966, 2 TMS (P) (Box-folder 3-1)
  AID 2 (Agency for International Development)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER'S NOTES RE AID ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON HEALTH MANPOWER 1966/10/10-11, AMs (Box-folder 3-2)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1966/10/ca, 7 TMs (P) (Box-folder 3-3)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLET AND JOURNAL 1963-1969, 2 Pamphlets/Journals (Box-folder 3-4)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1964-1967, 9 TLS (Box-folder 3-5)
  AID 3 (Agency for International Development)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1964-1965, 5 TL (CC) (Box-folder 3-6)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1964-1968, 7 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 3-7)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1965-1970, 21 TMs (P) (Box-folder 3-8)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS 1963-1967, 2 Pamphlets (Box-folder 3-9)
- MISCELLANEOUS FORMS, VOUCHERS, INVOICES 1963-1969, 14 Printed Forms (Box-folder 3-10)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1970, 33 TLS (Box-folder 4-1)
  AID 4 (Agency for International Development)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1966-1970, 11 TL (CC) (Box-folder 4-2)
- BILL PARKER TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1967/06/19, ALS (Box-folder 4-3)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO DEANE 1970/11/ca, ANS (Box-folder 4-4)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1970, 15 TLS/TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 4-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1963-1967, 10 TMs (P) (Box-folder 4-6)
- MEETING RESPONSE CARD AND RETURN ENVELOPE 1967/03/ca, Printed Card with Envelope (Box-folder 4-7)
- AID/W TO ANKARA AIDTO 1967/04/04, Airgram (Box-folder 4-8)
- MISCELLANEOUS FORMS 1958-1970, 21 Printed Forms (Box-folder 4-9)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969-1970, 3 TLS (Box-folder 4-10)
  AID 5 (Agency for International Development)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1969-1973, 8 TL (CC) (Box-folder 4-11)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970-1972, 3 ALS (Box-folder 4-12)
- DEPARTMENT OF STATE -- FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF CAMEROON BACKGROUND NOTES 1969/09, Pamphlet (Box-folder 4-13)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1968-1970, 7 TMs (P) (Box-folder 4-14)
- HERBERT T. WAGNER TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1968/11/26, TLS (P) (Box-folder 4-15)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO HERBERT T. WAGNER 1968/12/03, TL (P) (Box-folder 4-16)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1969, 5 TL (CC) (Box-folder 5-1)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969, 4 TLS (Box-folder 5-2)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1968-1969, 7 ALS (Box-folder 5-3)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969, 6 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 5-4)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1969, 8 TMs (P) (Box-folder 5-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL IN THOMAS H. HUNTER'S HAND 1969, 6 AMs (Box-folder 5-6)
- JOHN [] TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981/06/23, ALS (Box-folder 5-7)
  AC File
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1981, 4 TL (CC) (Box-folder 5-8)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981, 11 TLS (Box-folder 5-9)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981, 12 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 5-10)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINTS, NEWSCLIPPINGS, JOURNALS 1980-1981, 7 Reprints/Newsclippings/Journals (Box-folder 5-11)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1979-1981, 14 TMs (P) (Box-folder 5-12)
- OUTLINE FOR "INSTITUTIONAL REVIEW BOARD INFORMED CONSENT, CLINICAL TRIAL ETHICS" BY THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981, AMs (Box-folder 5-13)
- INSTITUTIONAL REVIEW BOARD: INFORMED CONSENT AND CLINICAL TRIAL ETHICS BY THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981/06/ca, AMs (Box-folder 5-14)
- ADDED REFERENCES, THOMAS H. HUNTER, "INSTITUTIONAL REVIEW BOARD: INFORMED CONSENT AND CLINICAL TRIAL ETHICS 1981/ca, AMs (Box-folder 5-15)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981, ALS, ANS (Box-folder 6-1)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1981, 5 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 6-2)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER'S NOTES RE: ETHICS 1987/09, AMs (Box-folder 6-3)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER'S NOTES RE: TALK AT WILLIAMSBURG N.D., AMs (Box-folder 6-4)
- TELEPHONE NUMBER OF MRS. [CLEMANS] N.D., AN (Box-folder 6-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS ANNOUNCEMENTS 1981, 5 Printed Forms (Box-folder 6-6)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1974-1981, 13 TMs (P) (Box-folder 6-7)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINTS AND JOURNALS 1966-1981, 9 Reprints/Journals (Box-folder 6-8)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1960-1976, 6 TLS (Box-folder 6-9)
  AAAS (American Academy of Arts and Sciences)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1960-1976, 11 TL (CC) (Box-folder 6-10)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1958-1980, 23 TLS/TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 6-11)
- ELECTION OF ACADEMY MEMBERS 1974/03, TMs (P) (Box-folder 6-11)
- HARVEY BROOKS TO FELLOWS OF THE ACADEMY 1975/05/14, TLS (P) (Box-folder 6-12)
- ELECTION OF ACADEMY MEMBERS 1974/03, TMs (P) (Box-folder 6-13)
- ELECTIONS OF ACADEMY MEMBERS 1974/03, TMs (P) (Box-folder 6-14)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS AND JOURNALS 1963-1975, 5 Pamphlets/Journals (Box-folder 6-15)
- MISCELLANEOUS FORMS AND ANNOUNCEMENTS 1965-1980, 8 Printed Forms (Box-folder 6-16)
- DEAN, DARTMOUTH MEDICAL SCHOOL TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/05/25, ALS (Box-folder 6-17)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1970, 5 TL (CC) (Box-folder 7-1)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1974-1975, 2 TLS (P) (Box-folder 7-2)
- NOTIFICATION OF ELECTION TO MEMBERSHIP IN THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF ARTS AND SCIENCES 1958/05/14, Certificate with AA (Box-folder 7-3)
- THE HOUSE OF THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF ARTS AND SCIENCES 1979/ca, Map (Box-folder 7-4)
- BULLETINS OF THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF ARTS AND SCIENCES 1963, 4 Pamphlets (Box-folder 7-5)
- DUES ANNOUNCEMENTS 1960-1963, 3 Printed Forms (Box-folder 7-6)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1965-1970, 9 TLS (Box-folder 7-7)
  AAAS 1 (American Association for the Advancement of Science)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1965-1968, 3 TL (CC) (Box-folder 7-8)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1965-1972, 14 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 7-9)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1958-1972, 25 TMs (P) (Box-folder 7-10)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINTS AND PAMPHLETS 1958-1968, 5 Reprints/Pamphlets (Box-folder 7-11)
- MISCELLANEOUS FORMS AND ANNOUNCEMENTS 1962-1967, 4 Printed Forms (Box-folder 7-12)
- [ ] TO [THOMAS H. HUNTER N.D., ANS (Box-folder 7-13)
  ABIM American Board of Internal Medicine
- A RECAPITULATION BY THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969/12/28, TMs (P) (Box-folder 7-14)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1961-1981, 4 TLS (P), 29 TL (CC) (Box-folder 8-1)
  ACCA (American Clinical and Climatological Association)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1961-1981, 28 TLS (Box-folder 8-2)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1964-1978, 32 TLS/TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 8-3)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS 1967/ca, 2 Pamphlets (Box-folder 8-4)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1973-1978, 4 TMs (P) (Box-folder 8-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS FORMS AND ANNOUNCEMENTS 1967-1978, 12 Printed Forms (Box-folder 8-6)
- F. TREMAINE BILLINGS JR. TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1961/12/11, TLS (Box-folder 9-1)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1963-1969, 6 TMs (P) (Box-folder 9-1)
  AMA (American Medical Association)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO F. TREMAINE BILLINGS JR. 1961/12/03, TL (CC) (Box-folder 9-2)
- AMERICAN CLINICAL AND CLIMATOLOGICAL ASSOCIATION CANDIDATES 1963, Printed Form (Box-folder 9-3)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1966-1975, 2 TL (CC) (Box-folder 9-4)
  ACP (American College of Physicians)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1978, 4 TLS (Box-folder 9-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS PROGRAMS 1975, 3 Printed Programs (Box-folder 9-6)
- MEMOS SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1967-1970, 3 TM (P) (Box-folder 9-7)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1962-1978, 9 TL (CC) (Box-folder 9-8)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962-1978, 11 TLS (Box-folder 9-9)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962-1970, 16 TLS/TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 9-10)
- J. MICHAELSON TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966/09/21, AM (Box-folder 9-11)
- MISCELLANEOUS VOUCHERS AND PROGRAMS 1966-1969, 5 Printed Forms (Box-folder 9-12)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS AND NEWSCLIPPING 1963-1966, 3 Pamphlets/Newsclippings (Box-folder 9-13)
- DIRECTOR, DIVISION OF INTERNATIONAL HEALTH TO PARTICIPANTS OF AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, AGENCY FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT REGISTER 1972/07/06, TM (Box-folder 9-15)
  APHA (American Public Health Association)
- SUSI KESSLER TO CONSULTANTS FOR INTERNATIONAL HEALTH PROGRAMS 1978/07, TM (Box-folder 9-16)
- MALCOLM H. MERRILL TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1971/10/06, TLS (Box-folder 9-17)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION INTERNATIONAL CONSULTANT AND TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE N.D., Pamphlet (Box-folder 9-18)
- PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATION IN INTERNATIONAL HEALTH -- THE AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION 1971/10/13, TMs (P) (Box-folder 9-19)
- CLYDE C. GREEN JR. TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1968/02/28, TLS (Box-folder 9-20)
  ASIM (American Society of Internal Medicine)
- MEMO AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1967-1968, 3 TLS/TM (P) (Box-folder 9-21)
- ASIM FORMS N.D., 2 Printed Forms (Box-folder 9-22)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS 1964-1968, 24 Pamphlets (Box-folder 9-22)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1974-1981, 17 TL (CC) (Box-folder 10-1)
  ASCI (American Society for Clinical Investigation)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1975-1980, 7 TLS (Box-folder 10-2)
- CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970-1980, 5 TLS/TL (P) (Box-folder 10-3)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS 1965-1975, 3 Pamphlets (Box-folder 10-4)
- MISCELLANEOUS PROGRAMS AND FORMS 1966-1980, 12 Printed Programs/Forms (Box-folder 10-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1970-1980, 11 TMs (P) (Box-folder 10-6)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO EDWARD HUTH 1978-1979, 2 TL (CC) (Box-folder 10-7)
  AIM (Annals of Internal Medicine)
- EDWARD J. HUTH TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1978-1979, 4 TLS, TLS (P) (Box-folder 10-8)
- EDWARD J. HUTH TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1979/01/24, Telegram (Box-folder 10-9)
- MARTHA NELSON TO EDWARD J. HUTH 1979/02/26, TL (CC) (Box-folder 10-10)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1974, 2 ALS (Box-folder 10-11)
  ABC (Architectural Barrier Advisory Committee)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1974, 2 TL (CC) (Box-folder 10-12)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1974, 2 TLS (Box-folder 10-13)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1973-1974, 10 TLS/TM (P) (Box-folder 10-14)
- MISCELLANEOUS NEWSCLIPPINGS AND RESOLUTION 1974, 4 Newsclippings/Printed Forms (Box-folder 10-15)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1974, 4 TMs (P) (Box-folder 10-16)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1976-1980, 4 TLS (Box-folder 10-17)
  AAMC 1 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- MARY B. WAGNER TO ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES ANNUAL MEETING 1979/10/08, TL (CC) (Box-folder 10-18)
- JOHN A. D. COOPER TO COUNCIL OF DEANS ET. AL. 1980/03/15, TM (P) (Box-folder 10-19)
- THE STUDENT AFFAIRS REPORTER (VOLUME X, NUMBER 1) 1980, Serial (Box-folder 10-20)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1980/ca, AMs, AMs (P), TMs (P) (Box-folder 10-21)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES 90TH ANNUAL MEETING PRELIMINARY PROGRAM 1979/11/03-08, Printed Program (Box-folder 10-22)
- SUBCOMMITTEE ON HEALTH AND THE ENVIRONMENT 1979, Printed Form (P) (Box-folder 10-23)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1965-1975, 3 TL (CC) (Box-folder 11-1)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1965-1975, 8 TLS (Box-folder 11-2)
- MEMOS AND POSTCARD SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966-1971, 6 TM (P), TPC (Box-folder 11-3)
- MISCELLANEOUS ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES NEWSLETTERS 1973-1975, 24 Newsletters (Box-folder 11-4)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS N.D., 2 Pamphlets (Box-folder 11-5)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1966-1977, 6 TMs (P) (Box-folder 11-6)
- WENDY H. WADDELL TO LIAISON OFFICERS FOR INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS 1973/10/23, TMS (P) (Box-folder 11-7)
  AAMC 2 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- WENDY H. WADDELL TO LIAISON OFFICERS FOR INTERNATIONAL ACTIVITIES 1973/10/23, TMS (P) (Box-folder 11-8)
- STATEMENT BY THE ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES ON MEDICARE HOSPITAL REIMBURSEMENT 1973/08, TMs (P) (Box-folder 11-9)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962/08/17, ALS (Box-folder 11-10)
  AAMC 3 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS 1963-1973, 3 TL (CC) (Box-folder 11-11)
- VARIOUS CORRESPONDENTS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962-1973, 3 TLS (Box-folder 11-12)
- MEMOS AND CORRESPONDENCE COPIES SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962-1973, 3 TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 11-13)
- WORKSHOPS REGISTRATION SHEET N.D., Printed Form (Box-folder 11-14)
- MISCELLANEOUS ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES PAMPHLETS 1962-1973, 3 Pamphlets (Box-folder 11-15)
- MISCELLANEOUS MANUSCRIPT MATERIAL 1961-1973, 8 TMs (P) (Box-folder 11-16)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962/10/10, Envelope (Box-folder 11-17)
  AAMC 4 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- MEMO AND CORRESPONDENCE COPY SENT TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1962, 2 TL/TM (P) (Box-folder 11-18)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINTS AND NEWSCLIPPING 1961-1962, 5 Reprints/Newsclippings (Box-folder 11-19)
- PROPOSED ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES COMMENTS AND POSITIONS 1978/08/16, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-1)
  AAMC 5 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- TRIP REPORT 1972/02/01-15, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-2)
- TRAVEL NOTES OF HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1966/10/29-11/26, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-3)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES DIVISION OF INTERNAL MEDICAL EDUCATION FOREIGN MEDICAL GRADUATE STUDY N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-4)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES DIVISION OF INTERNAL MEDICAL EDUCATION PROPOSED SYSTEMS ENGINEERING STUDY N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-5)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO COMMITTEE ON INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS IN MEDICAL EDUCATION 1966/01/ca, T Memo (P) (Box-folder 12-6)
- CHIENGMAI UNIVERSITY FACULTY OF MEDICINE 1965/10, Reprint (Box-folder 12-7)
- INSTITUTION GRANT PROGRAM 1967/02/15, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-8)
- QUIGG NEWTON TO ROBERT C. BERSON 1966/11/04, TL (P) (Box-folder 12-9)
- J. KELLUM SMITH TO ROBERT C. BERSON 1967/02/03, TL (P) (Box-folder 12-10)
- OPPORTUNITIES FOR SERVICE ABROAD N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-11)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO LIAISON OFFICERS 1967/02/09, T Memo (P) (Box-folder 12-12)
- LOCKHARD TO THOMAS H. HUNTER N. D., ALS with AN (Box-folder 12-13)
- MAKERERE UNIVERSITY COLLEGE N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-14)
- PUBLIC HEALTH COLLEGE AND TRAINING CENTER 1962/ca, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-15)
- UNSPECIFIED MANUSCRIPT 1966/10/24, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-16)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER AND HAROLD MARGULIES 1966/10/18, T Memo S (Box-folder 12-17)
- PAUL H. CODY TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1966/10/13, TLS (P) (Box-folder 12-18)
- PAUL H. CODY TO MRS. ERIC L. F. ARCHDEACON 1966/09/29, TLS (P) (Box-folder 12-19)
- SUBHASH SANGHOEE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966/10/18, TLS with Envelope (Box-folder 12-20)
- RUBY M. PAYNE TO SUBHASH SANGHOEE 1966/10/24, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-21)
- ITINERARY FOR DR. AND MRS. HYDE N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-22)
- ROBERT C. BERSON TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1966/09/16, T Memo with AA (Box-folder 12-23)
- ROBERT A. MOORE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1966/08/12, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-24)
- LEE POWERS TO JOHN WILSON 1966/07/18, TL (P) (Box-folder 12-25)
- ROBERT C. BERSON TO ASSOCIATION MEMBER 1966/07/22, TLS (Box-folder 12-26)
- SUMMARY STATEMENT ON HEALTH MANPOWER PLANNING N. D., TMs (P) with AA (Box-folder 12-27)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES SPECIAL MEETING 1966/07/19-20, Printed Form (Box-folder 12-28)
- ROBERT C. BERSON TO DR.MALONEY ET. AL. 1966/07/28, T Memo (P) with AN (Box-folder 12-29)
- THE FUTURE OF EDUCATION FOR THE HEALTH SCIENCES BY WARD DARLEY 1966/07/18, TMs (P) with AN (Box-folder 12-30)
- DR. BERSON TO DR. HUNTER N.D., AN (Box-folder 12-31)
- NOTE FOR EXECUTIVE COUNCIL 1966/ca, TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-32)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES ANNUAL REPORT 1974-1975, Pamphlet (Box-folder 12-33)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO L. THOMPSON BOWLES 1970/12/22, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-34)
  AAMC 6 (Association of American Medical Colleges)
- L. THOMPSON BOWLES TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/12/14, TLS (Box-folder 12-35)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO L. THOMPSON BOWLES 1970/12/14, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-36)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/12/04, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-37)
- [ ] TO DR. BLACKERBY N. D., TL (P) with AA (Box-folder 12-38)
- HAZEL B. DAVIS TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/10/05, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-39)
- L. THOMPSON BOWLES TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/07/29, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-40)
- DAVID ROCKEFELLER TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/07/24, Telegram (Box-folder 12-41)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO DAVID ROCKEFELLER 1970/07/17, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-42)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/07/09, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-43)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1970/07/10, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-44)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/07/06, TLS (Box-folder 12-45)
- A. R. EL-SADR TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1970/06/23, TLS (P) (Box-folder 12-46)
- A. R. EL-SADR TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1970/05/14, TLS (P) (Box-folder 12-47)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO A. R. EL-SADR 1970/07/10, TL (P) (Box-folder 12-48)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1970/07/02, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-49)
- LUCILLE S. BLOCH TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/05/07, TLS (Box-folder 12-50)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969/12/23, TLS with AA (Box-folder 12-51)
- ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN MEDICAL COLLEGES INTERNATIONAL PROGRAM N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-52)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO JACK SWARTWOOD 1970/01/09, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-53)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1970/01/06, TLS with PC (Box-folder 12-54)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO JOHN A. D. COOPER 1969/12/30, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-55)
- JOHN A. D. COOPER TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969/12/24, TLS (Box-folder 12-56)
- HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969/11/20, TLS (Box-folder 12-57)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO JOHN A. D. COOPER 1969/08/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-58)
- JOHN A. D. COOPER TO THOMAS H. HUNTER 1969/08/08, TLS (Box-folder 12-59)
- ISSUES IN HEALTH MANPOWER LEGISLATION N. D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 12-60)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO HENRY VAN ZILE HYDE 1969/11/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 12-61)
- THOMAS H. HUNTER TO BENEDICT J. DUFFY 1969/11/13, TL (CC) with AA (Box-folder 12-62)